Nabil Douss

Berlin, 13403 | +49 176 87823496

n.douss97@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/nabil-douss

Hey there! I'm a Senior Consultant in Indirect Tax Technology at EY with a tech background as a full-stack developer. I've spent 5 years building cool stuff with various technologies such as Next.JS, ASP.NET, and Python, while also unraveling the intricacies of business transactions through data analytics.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Consultant Oct 2023 - Present

EY Tax GmbH Steuerberatungsgesellschaft, Berlin

- Co-engineered a Next.JS web application for processing, querying and displaying business transactions.
- Co-developed and maintained a tax determination engine in C# with an ASP.NET API for analyzing, classifying, and evaluating the data quality and tax recording of SAP business transactions.
- Integrated a copilot chatbot into the Next.js application using Azure OpenAl models.
- Conceptualized and enabled various use cases and chat modes for the copilot, including:
 - Answering tax-related questions using a Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) process.
 - Interacting with transactional data in MongoDB.
 - Making API calls to the tax determination engine.
 - Making API calls to public services to verify the validity of VAT IDs.
- Mentored and managed a team consisting of 3 junior members.

Consultant Oct 2022 - Oct 2023

Ernst & Young GmbH Wirtschaftsprüfungsgesellschaft, Berlin

- Improved a backend server in JavaScript and GraphQL that processes real-time queries on transactions, while continuously maintaining an underlying MongoDB database.
- Co-developed a web-based dashboard in Vue.js for real-time data analysis, implementing and testing various components such as tables, filters, and charts.
- Created a reporting tool in C# for data analysis, enabling the automatic creation of spreadsheets, pivot tables, and graphs in Excel files.
- Converted a desktop solution into a web application using ASP.NET, optimizing backend processes such as data transfer, data analysis, communication with thirdparty APIs, and SQL Server database maintenance.
- Designed and implemented a user interface in C# and ASP.NET for maintaining data in a MongoDB database.
- Improved quality assurance measures including code review, defect analysis and correction, and created more than 80 unit-tests using C# and the XUnit framework.

Working Student Jun 2019 - Oct 2022

Ernst & Young GmbH Wirtschaftsprüfungsgesellschaft, Berlin

EDUCATION

Master of Science (M.S.) - Data Science & Engineering

Oct 2019 - Jun 2022

Technische Universität Berlin (Grade 1.2)

 Master thesis: "Multi-domain Sentiment Analysis with an Active Learning Mechanism". The thesis proposes three model architectures for binary sentiment analysis on multi-domain textual data using an Active Learning mechanism.

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) - Computer Science

Oct 2016 - Jan 2020

Technische Universität Berlin (Grade 1.5)

• Bachelor thesis: "An Analysis of Lightweight Cryptographic Algorithms".

PUBLICATIONS

ACM SAC Conference (SAC'23)

2023

Katerina Katsarou, Nabil Douss, and Kostas Stefanidis. 2023. REFORMIST: Hierarchical Attention Networks for Multi-Domain Sentiment Classification with Active Learning. In Proceedings of ACM SAC Conference (SAC'23). ACM, New York, NY, USA, Article 4, 10 pages.

SKILLS

IT-Skills

- Programming languages: JavaScript / Python / C# / Java
- Frameworks: React / NextJS / VueJS/ ASP .NET
- Machine Learning: PyTorch/Keras/Tenserflow/Scipy/Pandas
- Database Systems: MySQL / SQL Server / MongoDB

Language Skills

- German, Professional proficiency
- French, Professional proficiency
- English, Professional proficiency
- Arabic, Native language